Guide to the William C. Lynch Dennis Brain Collection ARS.0138
Archive of Recorded Sound
- Compact Discs, circa 1936-2011; 155 discs 123 CD-Rs; 32 compact discs
  - Non-commerical recordings, circa 1936-2011; 117 items 113 CD-Rs; 4 compact discs
    - Various radio specials relating to Brain, 1998-1991; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 142)
      Kaleidoscope. Berkeley, Michael, presenter. British Broadcasting Corporation. 1998 Barry Tuckwell's 60th Birthday. Bak, Richard, interviewer. Tuckwell, Barry, interviewee. 1991 March 10.
    - Rehearsal of music for the British Transport Film, Open House, and Mozart concert., 1951; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 143)
      Rehearsal of incidental music for the British Transport Film, Open House. Williams, Edward, 1921-, composer. Jame, Natalie, 1909-2008, oboe. James, Cecil, 1913-1999, bassoon. Morris, Gareth, flute. De Peyer, Gervase, 1926-, clarinet. Recorded at Riverside Studios, London.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Dennis Brain Ensemble. Hansen, Conrad, piano. Berliner Rundfunk, live broadcast. 1951 September 22.
    - Delius, Tchaikovsky, Britten, Strauss (Johann), Thomas, and Mozart, circa 1945-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 144)
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Messe des Lebens. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1953.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Andante. Extract. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1946 November 13-14.
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Canticle, no. 3. Aldeburgh Festival of Music and the Arts. British Broadcasting Corporation. Third Programme. 1955 June 22.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. An der schönen, blauen Donau. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England), Krips, Josef, conductor. 1947 October 17.
      Thomas, Ambroise, 1811-1896. Raymond. Overture only. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England), Neel, Boyd, conductor. 1945 January 10.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Idomeneo. Ouverture. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England), Neel, Boyd, conductor. December 15. No year noted.
    - Mozart, Mendelssohn, and Strauss (Johann II), 1947-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 145)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Schauspieldirektor. Sinfonia. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Neel, Boyd, conductor.1948 March 24.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Entführung aus dem Serail. Ouverture. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Neel, Boyd, conductor.1945 March 24.
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Capriccio brillant. Lympany, Moura, 1916-2005, piano. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Neel, Boyd, conductor. 1947 January 1.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Zigeunerbaron. Ouverture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1955 July 7.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. Kaiser-Walzer. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1955 July 7.
      Strauss, Johann, 1825-1899. An der schönen, blauen Donau. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1955 July 7-8.
    - Honegger, Hindemith, Mozart, and Blech, circa 1952-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 146)
      Honegger, Arthur, 1892-1955. Pastorale d'été. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra.
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Schwanendreher. William Primrose Chamber Orchestra; Pritchard, John, 1921-1989. Published 1955.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Lucio Silla. Ouverture. London Mozart Players; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1952 September 27.
      Radio interview with Blech, Harry, 1910-1999. BBC Radio 3. Discuss the formation of the London Mozart Players and London Wind Players.
    - Prokofiev and Shostakovich, March 1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 147)
      Prokofiev, Sergey, 1891-1953. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 25, D major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kurtz, Efrem, 1900-1995, conductor. 1957 March 12-13.
      Shostakovich, Dmitriĭ Dmitrievich, 1906-1975. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 10. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kurtz, Efrem, 1900-1995, conductor. 1957 March 4.
    - Delius, 1952 November-December; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 148)
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Appalachia (1903). Coulston, Sidney, 1910-1999, horn. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1952 November 6-7, 1952 November 13, 1952 December 18.
    - Bizet and Strauss (Richard), 1950-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 149)
      Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Jolie fille de Perth. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1950 February 6.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Rosenkavalier (Opera). Selections. Act 1, Part 1, The Princess' Bedroom. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1956 December 10-15, 1956 December 17-22.
    - Tchaikovsky, Brahms, and Bruckner., 1952-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 150)
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Andante cantabile con alcuna licenza. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1952 May 1, 1952 May 8, 1952 July 25, 1952 July 31.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Allegro non troppo, ma con brio. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1952 May 6-7, 1952 July 28, 1952 July 31.
      Bruckner, Anton, 1824-1896. Overture, G minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Matačić, Lovro von, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1956 January 16.
    - Beethoven, Granados, and Turina, circa 1952; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 151)
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 3, op. 55, E♭ major. Scherzo. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1952 November 20-22, 1952 December 1.
      Granados, Enrique, 1867-1916. Danzas españolas. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Schüchter, Wilhelm, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London.
      Turina, Joaquín, 1882-1949. Danzas fantásticas. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England). Kingsway Hall, London.
    - Sibelius and Weber, 1946-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 152)
      Sibelius, Jean, 1865-1957. Symphonies, no. 2, op. 43, D major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1955 July 18-19.
      Weber, Carl Maria von, 1786-1826. Beherrscher der Geister. Overture. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1946 March 12.
    - Wolf, Walton, Falla, and Kabalevsky. Additional radio interview with Jack Brymer., 1945-1975; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 153)
      Wolf, Hugo, 1860-1903. Italienische Serenade. Reger, Max, 1873-1916, arranger. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1945 July 2.
      Walton, William, 1902-1983. Scapino. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Susskind, Walter, 1913-1980, conductor. 1951 October 19.
      Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Sombrero de tres picos. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1946 June 5.
      Kabalevsky, Dmitry Borisovich, 1904-1987. Kola Bri︠u︡nʹon. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Schüchter, Wilhelm, conductor. 1953 November 26.
      Brymer, Jack. Talk on Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961. Given to the Sir Thomas Beecham Society. 1975. Includes excerpts from the 1950 Royal Philharmonic Orchestra tour of the United States of America.
    - Borodin and Smetana, 1951-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 154)
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 2, B minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1955 September 23.
      Smetana, Bedřich, 1824-1884. Prodaná nevěsta. Selections. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kubelík, Rafael, 1914-1996, conductor. 1951 September 4.
    - Lambert, Mozart, Villa-Lobos, and Wagner, 1948-1951; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 155)
      Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951. Music, orchestra. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Lambert, Constant, 1905-1951, conductor. British Broadcasting Corporation. 1948.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 166, E♭ major. London Wind Soloists; Blech, Harry, 1910-1999, conductor. 1946 September 27-28.
      Villa-Lobos, Heitor. Chôros, no. 4. Brain, Alfred, 1885-1966, horn. 1950.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Siegfried-Idyll. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1951 October 16.
    - Delius, 1946 November; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 156)
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Song of the high hills. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1946 November 22. Interlude: Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. Burton, Humphrey, 1931-, introduces Morris, Gareth. 1997 January 17.
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Brigg Fair. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra, Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1946 November 26.
    - Stravinsky and Mendelssohn, 1951-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 157)
      Stravinsky, Igor, 1882-1971. Vesna svi︠a︡shchennai︠a︡. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Markevitch, Igor, 1912-1983, conductor. 1951 November 12-13.
      Mendelssohn-Bartholdy, Felix, 1809-1847. Symphonies, no. 4, op. 90, A major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. 1955 August 12-13; 1955 August 16.
    - Rimsky-Korsakov, Balakirev, Respighi, 1955-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 158)
      Rimsky-Korsakov, Nikolay, 1844-1908. Svetlyĭ prazdnik. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962, conductor. 1956 February 13.
      Balakirev, Miliĭ Alekseevich, 1837-1910. Islameĭ. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962, conductor. 1956 February 8.
      Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Impressioni brasiliane. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Galliera, Alceo, conductor. 1955 March 18-19.
    - Hindemith and Mozart; Interview with Dennis Brain and BBC Radio special, 1952-1976; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 159)
      Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, interviewee. Carrington, Desmond, interviewer. Interview source unknown.
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Sonatas, horn, piano (1939). Matthews, Denis, piano. British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1953 July 12.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, horn, orchestra, K. 447, E♭ major. Süddeutscher Rundfunk. Sinfonie-Orchester; Müller-Kray, Hans, conductor. 1952 April 20.
      BBC Radio 4 program, Kaleodoscope. Review of Dennis Brain: a biography by Pettitt, Stephen. Matthews, Denis, provides an opinion on the book and also discusses Brain.
    - Hindemith, Delius, and Verdi; BBC Radio special., 1951-1979; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 160)
      BBC Radio 3 (or 4), Brymer, Jack "At Home". Discussion about Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957. 1979 November 7.
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Concertos, horn, orchestra. WDR Sinfonieorchester Köln; Keilberth, Joseph, conductor. 1951 January 22.
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Messe des Lebens. Prelude part 2 - "On the mountain"; Introduction - Andante. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1952 November 8; 1952 December 12-13.
      Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901. Falstaff. Selections. Act 3, Part 2. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1956 June.
    - Mozart, Bizet, Berlioz, Tchaikovsky, Wagner, 1944-1947; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 161)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 287, B♭ major. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1947 July 12.
      Bizet, Georges, 1838-1875. Arlésienne. Excerpts. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor. 1944 October 3; 1944 October 11.
      Berlioz, Hector, 1803-1869. Damnation de Faust. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1944 October 4.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Marche slave. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1944 October 4-5.
      Wagner, Richard, 1813-1883. Ring des Nibelungen. Götterdämmerung. Siegfrieds Rheinfahrt. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Oprichnik. Selections. Overture. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Fistoulari, Anatole, conductor. 1944 November 1.
    - Delius, Strauss (Richard), Dvorak, and Beethoven, 1951-1956; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 162)
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. In a summer garden. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. 1951 October 27.
      Delius, Frederick, 1862-1934. Irmelin (Orchestral work). Prelude. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor. 1944 June 8.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Concertos, horn, orchestra, no. 1, op. 11, E♭ major. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Boult, Adrian, 1889-1983, conductor. 1956 March 18.
      Dvořák, Antonín, 1841-1904. Legendy. No. 10. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Kubelík, Jan, conductor. 1956 March 18.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Symphonies, no. 3, op. 55, E♭ major. Trio movement only. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1952 November 20-22; 1952 December 1.
    - Smyth, 1946 November 5; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 163)
      Smyth, Ethel, 1858-1944. Concerto, violin, horn, orchestra. Grinke, Frederick, 1911-1987, violin. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962, conductor. 1946 November 5. Incomplete.
    - Essex and Smyth, 1936-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 164)
      Essex, Kenneth. Horn Concerto in 3 movements. BBC Scottish Symphony Orchestra. 1955 May 21.
      Smyth, Ethel, 1858-1944. Concerto, violin, horn, orchestra. Slow movement and part of last movement only. Brain, Aubrey, 1893-1955, horn. Brosa, Antonio, 1894-1979, violin. BBC Symphony Orchestra; Boult, Adrian, 1889-1983, conductor. 1936 November 8.
    - Bowyer and Strauss (Richard), circa 1953; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 165)
      Bowyer, R.W. Look to this day. London Chamber Orchestra. London Chamber Singers. Bernard, Anthony, conductor. First performance.
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Sonatinas, flutes (2), oboes (2), clarinets (4), basset horn, horns (4), bassoon, contrabassoon, TrV 291, E♭ major. London Baroque Ensemble; Haas, Karl, 1900-1970, conductor. First broadcast performance. 1953 January 28.
      Technical note
      Test tone and voice audible during the first movement of the Strauss Sonatina. Appears approximately 30 seconds in. Present on the original recording.
    - Dohnanyi, undated; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 167)
      Dohnányi, Ernő, 1877-1960. Sextets, piano, winds, strings, op. 37, C major.
    - Janacek, undated; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 168)
      Janáček, Leoš, 1854-1928. Mládí. Dennis Brain Ensemble. BBC Studio Concert. Performance introduced by Aprahamian, Felix.
    - Strauss (Richard), 1947 October 19; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 169)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Symphonia domestica. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England). British Broadcasting Corporation, live broadcast. 1947 October 19.
    - Music in Air Force Blue, 2005 April 22; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 170)
      BBC Radio 4 program entitled Music in Air Force Blue, The Story of the RAF Symphony Orchestra. Features interviews with Morris, Gareth and Singleton, Gil. Also features archive recordings of: Respighi, Ottorino, 1879-1936. Boutique fantasque; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Water music. No. 6, Air, Harty, arranger; Handel, George Frideric, 1685-1759. Water music. No. 8, Bourrée, Harty, arranger. RAF Symphony Orchestra; Wing Commander O'Donnell, R, conductor. 2005 April 22.
    - Strauss (Richard), 1952 July-August; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 172)
      Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Liebe der Danae. 1952 August 14. Strauss, Richard, 1864-1949. Letzte Lieder. 1952 July 12.
    - Tchaikovsky, 1944-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 173)
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Andante cantabile con alcuna licenza. National Symphony Orchestra (London, England); Beer, Sidney, conductor. 1944 January 8.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Andante cantabile con alcuna licenza. Cursue, Alfred or Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, horn. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Kletzki, Paul, conductor. 1946 November 14.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Andante cantabile con alcuna licenza. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Von Karajan, Herbert, conductor. 1953 January 19.
      Tchaikovsky, Peter Ilich, 1840-1893. Symphonies, no. 5, op. 64, E minor. Andante cantabile con alcuna licenza. Cursue, Alfred or Civil, Alan, horn. 1957 February 22.
    - Mozart, Hindemith, and Poulenc, 1957 July 30; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 174)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Divertimenti, K. 270, B♭ major. Salzburger Festspiele. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1957 July 30.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Salzburger Festspiele. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1957 July 30.
      Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963. Kammermusik, no. 1. Salzburger Festspiele. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1957 July 30.
      Poulenc, Francis, 1899-1963. Sextet, piano, flute, oboe, clarinet, bassoon, horn. Salzburger Festspiele. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1957 July 30.
    - Faure, Goldmark, Mozart, Suppe, Waldteufel, and Borodin, circa 1950-1955; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 175)
      Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924. Masques et bergamasques. Chamber Orchestra of London; Bernard, Anthony, 1891-1963, conductor.
      Fauré, Gabriel, 1845-1924. Pavan, orchestra, op. 50, F♯ minor. Chamber Orchestra of London; Bernard, Anthony, 1891-1963, conductor.
      Goldmark, Carl, 1830-1915. Ländliche Hochzeit. Royal Philharmonic Orchestra; Beecham, Thomas, Sir, 1879-1961, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1952 May 5-8.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Nozze di Figaro. Aprite un po' quegl' occhi. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Robertson, conductor. 1950 March 15.
      Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895. Schöne Galathée. Ouvertüre. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Schwartz, conductor. 1955 June 30.
      Suppé, Franz von, 1819-1895. Schöne Galathée. Ouvertüre. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England). Chapman, Edmund, horn. 1955 January 18.
      Waldteufel, Emil, 1837-1915. Patineurs. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Krips, Josef, conductor. 1955 January 5.
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 2, B minor. Andante. Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1955 September 23. Incomplete.
    - Bruckner, 1954 October-December; 1 compact disc (Audio 2, Disc 176)
      Bruckner, Anton, 1824-1896. Symphonies, no. 4, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Matačić, Lovro von, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1954 October 12-13; 1954 December 11 and 14.
    - Borodin, Falla, and Tomlinson, 1951-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 1, Disc 177)
      Borodin, Aleksandr Porfirʹevich, 1833-1887. Symphonies, no. 2, B minor. Andante. Malko, Nicolai, 1883-1961, conductor. 1955 September 23.
      Falla, Manuel de, 1876-1946. Sombrero de tres picos. Danza del molinero. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Markevitch, Igor, 1912-1983, conductor. 1951 November 14; 1952 September 13.
      Tomlinson, Ernest, 1924-. Rhapsody and Rondo. Rehearsal recording. Royal Festival Hall (London, England). 1957 June 22.
    - Seiber, 1948; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 178)
      Seiber, Mátyás, 1905-1960. Phantasies, flute, horn, strings. Featured in the 1948 animated film The Magic Canvas. Blech String Quartet. 1948. US publication 1955.
    - Mozart and Berkeley, 1954 May-October; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 179)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1954 May 19; 1954 May 23.
      Berkeley, Lennox, 1903-1989. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 44. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1954 June 15-16.
    - Mozart, 1953-1954; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 183)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Concertos, piano, orchestra, K. 449, E♭ major. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cameron, Basil, 1884-1975, conductor. 1953 January 13.
    - Britten, 1953 November 25-27; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 184)
      Britten, Benjamin, 1913-1976. Serenade, tenor, horn, string orchestra, op. 31. New Symphony Orchestra of London; Goossens, Eugene, 1893-1962, conductor. 1953 November 25-27.
    - Mozart and Brahms, circa 1954-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 185)
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, K. 452, E♭ major. Horsley, Colin, piano. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1954 May 19; 1954 May 24.
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Trios, piano, violin, horn, op. 40, E♭ major. Preedy, Cyril, piano. Salpeter, Max, violin. Live broadcast. 1957 February 15.
      Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus, 1756-1791. Quintets, horn, violin, violas, cello, K. 407, E♭ major. Carter String Trio.
    - Marais, Malipiero, Beethoven, and Dukas, circa 1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 186)
      Marais, Marin, 1656-1728. Pièces de violes, 4e livre. 1ère partie. Suitte, no. 5. Basque. Parry, Wilfrid, piano. Includes interview with Plomley, Roy, 1914-1985. Edinburgh International Festival. 1957 August 24.
      Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, and Morris, Gareth, remember Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, in the RAF Central Band.
      Malipiero, Gian Francesco, 1882-1973. Dialoghi, no. 4. Dennis Brain Ensemble. 1957 August 24.
      Excerpt from a lecture-recital by Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957 on The Early Horn. 1955 July 28.
      Morris, Gareth, discusses Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, leading his wind ensemble.
      Aprahamian, Felix, talks about Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957. Aprahamian discusses Brain's organ playing and assesses his future as a horn player.
      Beethoven, Ludwig van, 1770-1827. Quintets, piano, oboe, clarinet, horn, bassoon, op. 16, E♭ major. Parry, Wilfrid, piano. Dennis Brain Ensemble.
      Morris, Gareth, and Del Mar, Norman, 1919-1994, sum up Brain, Dennis, 1921-1957, as a person, and Parry, Wilfrid, pays a final tribute.
      Dukas, Paul, 1865-1935. Villanelle, horn, piano. Parry, Wilfrid, piano.
    - Neapolitan Songs: Cardillo, Campese, De Crescenzo, and De Curtis, 1946 September 28; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 187)
      Cardillo, S. (Salvatore). Core 'ngrato. Infantino, Luigi, tenor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), Patanè, Giuseppe, 1932-1989, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1946 September 28.
      Campese. Sunnanne a Pusilleco. Infantino, Luigi, tenor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), Patanè, Giuseppe, 1932-1989, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1946 September 28.
      De Crescenzo, Vincenzo, 1875-1964. Rondine al nido. Infantino, Luigi, tenor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), Patanè, Giuseppe, 1932-1989, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1946 September 28.
      De Curtis, Ernesto, 1875-1937. Torna a Surriento. Infantino, Luigi, tenor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England), Patanè, Giuseppe, 1932-1989, conductor. Abbey Road Studios (London, England). 1946 September 28.
    - Brahms, 1953 May 21-22; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 188)
      Brahms, Johannes, 1833-1897. Symphonies, no. 1, op. 68, C minor. Philharmonia Orchestra (London, England); Cantelli, Guido, conductor. Kingsway Hall, London. 1953 May 21-22.
    - Brahms, 1956-1957; 1 CD-R (Audio 2, Disc 189)